oldpueblotraders.com 2015-09-18

# Privacy and Security | Old Pueblo Traders

Please note that the privacy and security policies and data collection processes for these Orchard Brands family of related companies may differ from this Privacy and Security Policy published for Old Pueblo Traders. Please refer to the website for each of these related companies for their particular privacy and security policy detailing how that affiliated company handles your privacy concerns and personal information. 

* * *

**What kind of information do we collect?**

We use a variety of methods to gather information to help ensure that your shopping experience is as efficient and accommodating as possible. We may obtain personal information about you from various sources, including through your communications with us. We also collect certain information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies and pixel tags. 

* * *

__**Information you provide and how we use it**__  
You may choose to provide personal information to us in a number of ways, such as when you: 

  * • Request a catalog or information about our products and services
  * • Visit our website, or outlet locations
  * • Create an online shopping account
  * • Purchase, return, or exchange a product by phone, mail or online
  * • Visit store locations, as applicable
  * • Contact our call center or customer service desk
  * • Participate in a promotion, contest or survey
  * • Provide us with comments or suggestions

_Types of information you may provide_  
The types of information you may provide to us include: 

  * • Contact information such as name, mailing address, phone number, and email address
  * • Age and date of birth
  * • Gender
  * • Username and password
  * • Payment information (such as your payment card number, expiration date, delivery address and billing address)
  * • Demographic and preference information such as product purchase history
  * • Information you provide about other people, such as a gift recipient
  * • Information provided to us by Facebook when you use one of our Facebook apps (such as your name, profile picture, likes, location, friend list and other information described in the Facebook app sign-up page) 

_How we may use information you provide_

We may use the information you provide to:  

  * • Assist you in customer service communications
  * • Administer "My Account" information, online forms, and other website features
  * • Enable you to check out and complete your purchases, and to fill and ship your orders
  * • Send you special announcements or promotional information about new products or services and upcoming events, and to allow our Orchard Brands family or affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners to do the same
  * • Send you printed catalogs in the mail
  * • Share your information as necessary, with trusted third-party companies that provide support services to us or with which we partner to provide services, including special programs, offers and discounts
  * • Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; analyzing our products; performing data analytics; and performing accounting, auditing and other internal functions)
  * • Operate and communicate with you about our Facebook apps
  * • Comply with applicable legal requirements, relevant industry standards and our policies
  * • Protect your legal rights, our legal rights, or the legal rights of third parties

We may supplement the information listed above with information listed above with information that is collected automatically when you visit our website, and information acquired from our joint marketing partners, from third parties, and from our Orchard Brands affiliated companies.

_Emails_   

We may use your e-mail address to notify you about the status of your order, provide customer service information or to answer your questions and requests. We may also occasionally send you our e-mail updates, sales notifications, or other promotional information about our products and services or about the products and services of our Orchard Brands affiliated companies or trusted third party partners that may be of interest to you.

_Telephone Contact_  

If you provide us with your phone number, you may receive telephone contact from us for customer service communications, (for example, to inquire about an order you have placed). If you call our customer service toll-free number, we may ask you for personal identification information, depending on the nature of your request, to better assist you with your requests and questions. We may retain this information to help meet your future needs. 

We may occasionally use your phone number to contact you with updates, sales notifications, or other promotional information about our products and services or those of our Orchard Brands affiliated companies or trusted third party partners in which you may be interested. We may also make your personal information available to our Orchard Brands affiliated companies and our other trusted third party partners to enable them to contact you directly with their promotional information, such as information about their products and services, sales and other promotions.

_In-store Shopping_  

When you visit one of our stores or outlet locations and pay using a credit or debit card, we may retain a history of your purchases to process future orders and to better assist you. If you want to return or exchange purchase merchandise, we may ask you for personal identification information such as the credit card used for the purchase or a picture ID to help prevent fraud.

_Contests, Promotions, or Surveys_  

If you participate in a contest, promotion, sweepstakes offering, or survey (whether online, over the phone, by mail, or at one of our outlet stores), we may use information you provide to manage your entry, to notify you if you are a winner, or to fulfill promotional obligations. At the time of your entry or registration for a specific promotion, survey, contest, or sweepstakes, we will provide you with the rules governing such promotion, survey, contest, or sweepstakes.

* * *

**__Information we collect by automated means and how we use it__**

To improve our websites and to make your online experience more enjoyable, when you visit our websites we collect certain information by automated means, using cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies.

_Cookies, Web Server Logs and Pixel Tags_

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer's hard drive when you visit our websites. We use cookies to tell us who you are, tailor our products and services to suit your personal interests, estimate the number of visitors to our websites, track visits to pages within our websites, process your order, track your status in our promotions, contests and sweepstakes, and/or analyze our customers' visiting patterns. Cookies do not contain information such as name or credit card information. Most browsers are preset to accept cookies and are used to make online visits easier and faster for you. Cookies are not required for you to browse our websites. Please note, however, that without cookies you will not be able to shop or place an order on our websites. In such cases, to place orders, please call us at 1-800-362-8400.

In conjunction with obtaining information through cookies, our web servers may log details such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone in which your device is located. The web server logs also may record information such as the address of the web page that linked you to our site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet.

To control which web servers collect this information, we may place "pixel tags" (also called "web beacons" or "clear gifs"), which are tiny graphic images on our websites, to help us gather knowledge about how you use our websites.

_Third Party Web Analytics Services_  

We may use third party web analytics services on our websites, such as Google Analytics. The service providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons to help us analyze how visitors use the site. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to these service providers, who use the information to evaluate use of the website. To disable the Google Analytics cookie and any other third party web analytics service provider cookies, some browsers indicate when a cookie is being sent and allow you to decline cookies on a case-by-case basis.

_Targeted Advertising_   

We also may contract with third-party advertising networks that collect IP addresses and other information through the use of cookies, web server logs and web beacons on our websites and e-mails and on third-party websites and e-mails. They use this information to provide advertisements about products and services tailored to your interests (including for companies not affiliated with us). You may see these advertisements on our websites and other websites. This process also helps us manage and track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts.

_How we may use information collected by automated means_   

We may use the information we collect through automated means on our websites for market research, data analytics and system administration purposes, such as to determine whether you?ve visited us before or are new to the site, and for compliance with our legal obligations, policies and procedures, including compliance with relevant industry standards. We may combine the information we collect through automated means with other information we have collected from you. This information may be used to improve our websites, to personalize your online experience, to focus our communications with you to items of the most interest to you, to determine the effectiveness of our advertising, and for other internal business purposes to improve your shopping experience with us. We also may use the information in other ways for which specific notice is provided at the time of collection.

* * *

**How do we share your information?**  
We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information we collect about you, except as described here. We may share your personal information with:

 _Orchard Brands Affiliated Companies_

To provide you with other marketing information or promotions that may be of interest to you, we may disclose your personal information to our other Orchard Brands affiliated companies. We may also make your name, postal address and transactional information available to our Orchard Brands affiliated companies so that you may receive mailings directly from them about products and services that may be of interest to you.

 _Authorized Third Party Service Providers_

Certain service providers perform services on our behalf based on our instructions. We do not authorize these service providers to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. Examples of these service providers include entities that process credit card payments, fulfill orders, provide web hosting, manage our marketing and promotions activities.

_Other Trusted Third Parties_

We may, from time to time, partner with third parties to provide you with special offers. If you elect to take advantage of such an offer, you will be eligible to transact with such third party partner only if you provide them your personal information directly. We may make your name, postal address and transactional information available to certain trusted third party partners so that you may receive mailings directly from them about products and services that may be of interest to you. Also, some of our Facebook apps may share information collected through those apps with your Facebook friends or other Facebook users.

 _By Law_

In certain instances, we may disclose information about you (1) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (2) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (3) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal activity.

 _Sale of Business_  

We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event that Orchard Brands Corporation, or any of its subsidiary companies or any part of any of them implicating the Old Pueblo Traders business(es), sells or transfers all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy. Following such a sale or transfer, you may contact the entity to which we transferred your personal information with any inquiries concerning the processing of that information.

* * *

**How can you control the use of your information?**

We offer you certain choices in connection with the personal information we collect from you, such as how we use the information and how we communicate with you. To update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit a request, please contact us as specified below.

_Account Management_   

You can contact us at any time to review, change or delete certain personal information. Simply call our customer service specialists at 1-800-362-8410.

_E-mails_   

If you do not want to receive our electronic newsletter or promotional e-mails, you may unsubscribe at any time by clicking on "unsubscribe" at the bottom of any of our promotional e-mails or by contacting us as indicated below. It may take up to 10 days to process your unsubscribe request.

_Catalogs_   

If you do not wish to receive our printed catalogs, please contact our customer service specialists at 1-800-362-8410. When you give us your name and address as it appears on the mailing label, we will remove your contact information from our mailing list. Please allow several weeks for the catalogs to stop, as catalog delivery is scheduled well in advance.

_Telephone Contact_   

If you do not wish to receive telephone calls from us regarding our sales notifications or promotions, please contact our customer service specialists at 1-800-362-8410. Please note that we may continue to contact you by telephone for customer service communications (such as in relation to orders that you have previously placed with us). It may take up to 10 days to process your phone request.

_Facebook App Opt-Out_  
To remove or delete our apps from your Facebook account, follow the [instructions ](https://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=170585223002660) provided by the Facebook Help Center. _Sharing Information with Third Parties_   

If you would rather that we did not share your personal information with our Orchard Brands affiliated companies or our third party partners for their direct marketing purposes, please send your full name, address and customer number to our mailing address listed at the end of this privacy policy. Please note that even if you opt out of having your information shared with third parties in this way, we may still disclose your information to third parties in other circumstances as described in this privacy policy, for example, where required to enable our third party service providers to provide services to us, and where required by law.

Please also note that where we have previously disclosed personal information to an Orchard Brands affiliated company or third party partner prior to your opting out, that company's use of your information will be governed by its privacy policy. If you want to change how information is used by an Orchard Brands affiliate company or third party (for example, by opting-out of receiving emails or telephone communications from that company), you must contact that company or party directly. We cannot alter or remove your information from any of our Orchard Brands affiliated companies' or third party partners' databases.

* * *

**How do we safeguard your information?**

Protecting the safety of your personal information is important to us. We maintain appropriate technical, administrative and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. When you enter your personal information on our websites, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to protect your information as it is transmitted to us. As an additional security check, you may want to look at the URL or Location line of your browser to ensure that the first characters of the address changes from ?http? to ?https?. If you are not comfortable shopping online at our websites, please feel free to place your order with us at the number listed on the websites.

_Secure Shopping_   

Where our websites permit you to enter credit card or other billing information, we use industry-standard encryption technologies to encrypt that information while it is being transmitted. In addition, we make commercially acceptable efforts to stay up to date with best practices regarding the protection of information in connection with transactions occurring over the Internet.

_Phone Orders_   

Some versions of popular web browsers and some firewalls do not permit communication through secure servers like the ones we use to process orders. If your web browser cannot support this level of security, you will not be able to order products through our websites. If so, you may place orders by calling us toll-free at 1-800-362-8400.

We follow industry practices to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, but no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us over the Internet. Also, please note that e-mail is not encrypted and is not considered a secure means of transmitting sensitive information such as credit card numbers.

* * *

**Links To Other Websites**

Please remember that this Privacy and Security Policy applies only to the Old Pueblo Traders not to the other Orchard Brands family of related companies. The other Orchard Brands family of companies have their own privacy policies which may differ from this Privacy and Security Policy. In addition, our websites may include links that take you to other websites for outside business partners, vendors and advertisers. These third party websites have separate privacy and data collection practices. We have no control over such websites, and are not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or information-gathering practices of other entities or websites.

* * *

**Children's Privacy**

Our websites are not directed towards children. We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under 13 years of age on our websites. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of 13 on our websites, we will delete the information from our records.

* * *

**California Privacy Rights**

In certain circumstances, California law entitles California residents to request us to provide, free of charge and no more than once per calendar year, a list of the categories of the residents? personal information disclosed by us to third parties for such third parties' direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, together with the names and addresses of all such third parties and a description of such third parties' businesses, if not already reasonably apparent from the third parties' names. If you are a California resident and would like to receive such information, please contact us using the mailing address at the end of this Privacy and Security Policy.

* * *

**Changes to the Privacy Statement**

We reserve the right to change, modify or amend this Privacy and Security Policy from time to time and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. We will post a notice on our Websites to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy and Security Policy and indicate at the top of the policy when it was most recently updated. We encourage you to periodically review our current Privacy and Security Policy.

* * *

**How to Contact Us**

Our customers come first. If you have any concerns or questions, you can contact us by:

href="mailto:customerservice@OldPuebloTraders.com">customerservice@oldpueblotraders.com 
  * Writing to us at Old Pueblo Traders, P.O. Box 281, Jessup, PA 18434-0281
  * Calling us toll-free at 1-800-362-8410

* * *

**Conflict in Terms**

It is our goal to make our privacy practices easy to understand. We have created this easy-to-read privacy policy with that goal in mind. Some browsers utilize privacy enhancing technology to translate our privacy policy into a computer readable format. The technology then requires that the computer format be translated back into human readable format for you to read. This translation back into human readable format is often referred to as a "Policy Summary"; it is possible that through these translations, the Policy Summary may unintentionally end up being inconsistent with the privacy policy upon which it is based. It might fail to address an issue or it might address an issue not raised in our privacy policy. For this reason, you should rely on our privacy policy as the most accurate and definitive description of our practices.

* * *
